Arinze Ezeokwuegbu

Experienced software engineer with over 3 years of extensive experience designing and developing software solutions for various industries. Strong knowledge of various web application technologies, MERN stack as well as testing experience. Ability to work effectively in a team and deliver high-quality software on time.

7, Asajon Way, Eti-Osa 106104, Sangotedo, Lagos State, Nigeria.

Mobile: +2348134014148

Email:

darlingtonarinze1995@gmail.com **Github:** https://github.com/daceze95

Linkedin:

www.linkedin.com/in/arinze-ezeokwu

<u>egbu</u>

EXPERIENCE

Decagon — Software Engineer

JUNE 2022 - Date

- Experience with the SDLC process and agile development methodologies
- Developing and maintaining software applications using technologies such as Node.JS, Express.JS, Typescript, etc
- Collaborating with other team members, including designers, developers, and project managers, to plan and execute projects
- Creating and implementing database systems to store and manage data
- Designing and implementing user interfaces and user experiences
- Debugging and troubleshooting issues with software applications
- Testing software applications to ensure they are of high quality and free of errors

Webbiit Technologies, Benin — Web Developer

OCTOBER 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- Introduced to Web design and Development (web structuring, web architecture, wire-framing, and introduction to HTML5 and CSS3).
- Learned how to use WordPress and other CMS tools to design web applications.
- Website development using WordPress
- Speed optimization and Search Engine Optimization
- Web programming using JavaScript

PROJECTS

DEVELOPMENT OF LOGISTIC WEB APPLICATION

A logistic project that coordinates the movement of resources from one location to another destination at your convenience.

Technologies Used - NodeJs, ExpressJs, Google map API,

Paystack API

Link: https://swift-rider.netlifv.app

TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Tailwind
- Javascript
- Typescript
- React
- Redux
- React Hooks
- Rest API
- Nodejs
- Angular
- WordPress
- Express Framework
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Kubernetes
- GCP
- AWS
- Docker
- CI/CD
- Postgresql
- Heroku
- Jira
- Version Control with Git and Github.
- Test-Driven Development.

STAR WARS PICTURE GALLERY:

A project that displays all the star-wars characters and a little bio-data about them.

Technologies Used - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Swapi API.

Link: https://arinze-ezeokwuegbu.netlify.app/

3 COLUMN CARD PREVIEW

A frontend project that utilizes flexbox to make a preview card column responsive across various devices.

Technologies Used - HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Link: https://arinze-darlington.netlify.app/

E-LEARNING PLATFORM

A software application to deliver educational content over the internet.

Technologies Used - NodeJs, ExpressJs, Paystack API, ReactJs, MongoDB

EDUCATION

University of Jos, Plateau State, Nigeria — B.Sc.

FEBRUARY 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2019

CERTIFICATION

Scrumstudy: Scrum Fundamentals Certified.

Jobberman: Jobberman Soft Skills Course.

Google Digital Skills for Africa: The Fundamentals of

Digital Marketing.